Guide to the Stevens family papers, [ca. 1775-2010]
Stevens family papers, [ca. 1775-2010]
- Series IX. Audio/Visual Materials
  - Other Formats
    - Consolidated Numerical Index, 1880-1889 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Consolidated Alphabetical Index, 1880-1889 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Contents of File C.: \Cornell \ 1880-1887.CON, 1888-1889 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Fund records, reunion records, reunion correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Personal correspondences and pictures (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Cornell Class of 1945 Reunion items and photographs, 1945-1995 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Fund Reunion Campaigns, 2004 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Class of 1945 directory, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Alumni News Columns, Lamb's Wools, minutes from meetings, fellowship honorees, 1945-1964 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Cornell Class of 1945 and reunion materials, stationery, 1995-2000 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - MU-1385 – three football pins (2 Cornell, 1 Harvard) (Box 92)
    - MU-1386 – two Cornell scarves (Box 92)
- Series X. Books Related To The Family
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume I: The Genealogy of Otho Stevens (1702-1771), Together With the Kent, Hills, Hastings, Smith, Proctor, Sproule, and Associated Lines, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 1982 (Box 64, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume II: The Genealogy of John Christian Croll (1707-1758), Together With Garber, Ivins, Shreve, Knowles, Freeman, Prence, Brewster, Mayo, Higgins, Linnell and Associated Lines, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 1985 (Box 64, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume III: The Genealogy of Christian G. Knauss (1830-1885), Together With Bahret, Binetsch, Nickse, Reumann, Weigand, Speer, Feyerabend, Hess and Associated Lines, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 1988 (Box 65, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume IV: The Genealogy of Robert Pond (?-1637), Together With Shepherd, Lindsay, Churchill, Foote, Dunbar, Conant, Benjamin and Associated Lines, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 1990 (Box 66, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume V: Errata and Addenda to Volumes I through IV, Ancestral Charts and Consolidated Index, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 1991 (Box 67, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, Volume VI: Errata and Addenda II, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, 2001 (Box 67, Folder -)
  - Ancestry of the Children of Robert Croll Stevens and Jane Elanor (Knauss) Stevens, compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, final page proofs for all volumes, 1982-2001 (Box 94, Folder -)
  - The Life and Times of Alden Sprague Stevens, 1795-1874, edited by Robert Croll Stevens, 1975 (Box 68, Folder -)
  - Robert Sproule Stevens, 1888-1968: Transcript of Interview (July 6-10, 1965), compiled by Robert Croll Stevens, n.d. (post 1969) (Box 68, Folder -)
  - Journals and Poems of [Helen] Pauline Croll Stevens (Box 69, Folder -)
  - Journal, by Helen Pauline Croll [transcripted by Robert Croll Stevens], 3/14/1903 - 1/17/1907 (Box 69, Folder -)
  - Journal, by Pauline Croll Stevens [transcripted by Robert Croll Stevens], 4/2/1924 - 4/11/1935 (Box 69, Folder -)
  - Where Sunbeams Dwell, written by Pauline Croll Stevens, edited by Robert Croll Stevens, 1993 (Box 69, Folder -)
- Series XI. Transcriptions
  - Consolidated Index of Names (excluding the Stevens & Smith Business Papers), 1746-1855 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Consolidated Index of Documents (excluding the Stevens & Smith Business Papers), 1746-1855 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Transcripts, 1764-1797 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - XI-A. Alden Sprague Stevens Generation
    - Alden Sprague Stevens (1795-1874)
      - Diaries/Journals, 1831, 1861 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Personal Correspondence, 1814-1868 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Golden wedding anniversary papers, 1868 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Estate papers, 1874 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Business correspondence, 1824-1862 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Addresses/Speeches, 1832-1867 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Misc, 1868 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Addresses/Speeches, 1869, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Articles/Editorials/Newspaper clippings, 1857 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Certificates, 1842 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Sheriff's documents, 1825-1827 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Diary, 1871 (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Article, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Ascha Floyd (Smith) Stevens (1796-1882)
      - Correspondence, 1817-1869 (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Diary, 1857 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Robert Hastings Stevens (1802-1889)
      - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Albert Gallatin Stevens (1818-1872)
      - Writings/Publications/Speeches, 1837-1839, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Sarah Caroline (Greene) Stevens (1833-1875)
      - Correspondence (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Writings, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - XI-B. Robert (Wadleigh) Smith Stevens Generation
    - Caroline Eliza Floyd (Stevens) Briggs (1821-1893)
      - Certificate, 1844 (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence Received, 1838-1862 (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence Sent, 1850-1868 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Rufus Briggs (1820-1892)
      - Correspondence, 1845-1861 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Stevens family-related transcripts from other collections (mostly RWSS and ASS), 1857 (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Stevens family-related transcripts from other collections (mostly RWSS and ASS), 1858 (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Stevens family-related transcripts from other collections (mostly RWSS and ASS), 1859 (Box 80, Folder 23)
      - Stevens family-related transcripts from other collections (mostly RWSS and ASS), 1860-68 (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Robert (Wadleigh) Smith Stevens (1824-1893)
      - Diary, 1835 (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Personal correspondence, 1836-1860 (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Diary/Journal, 1841-1845 (Box 80, Folder 27)
      - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1857-1893 (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - Certificates (professional)Contracts: deeds, insurance, leases, mortgages, 1844-1868 (Box 80, Folder 29)
      - Business correspondence, 1847-1858 (Box 80, Folder 30)
      - Index by Name & Commodity, Stevens & Smith Letter Book, 1850-1856 (Box 80, Folder 31)
      - Index by Date, Stevens & Smith Letter Book, 1850-1856 (Box 80, Folder 32)
      - Index - Copybook "From R.S.S.", 1850-1856 (Box 80, Folder 33)
      - Business correspondence: Copybook "From R.S.S.), 1850-1856 (Box 80, Folder 34-39)
      - Consolidated Index of Names, 1856-1859 (Box 80, Folder 40)
      - Consolidated Index of Documents, 1856-1859 (Box 80, Folder 41)
      - Index of Letters and Letterbooks, 1856-1859 (Box 80, Folder 42)
      - Department of the Interior Office of Indian Affairs, 1857-1874/ (Box 80, Folder 43)
      - Index of Names/Index of Letters, Lecompton Letter Book, 1858-60 (Box 80, Folder 44)
      - Lecompton Letter Book, 1858-60 (Box 80, Folder 45-48)
      - Index of Names/Index of Letters, Letter Book of Letters To RWSS, 1859-60 (Box 80, Folder 49)
      - Letter Book of Letters To RWSS, 1859-60 (Box 80, Folder 50-53)
      - Business correspondence, 1859 (Box 80, Folder 54)
      - Business correspondence, Jan. 1860 (Box 80, Folder 55)
      - Business correspondence, Feb. 1860 (Box 80, Folder 56)
      - Business correspondence, March 1860 (Box 80, Folder 57)
      - Business correspondence, April 1860 (Box 80, Folder 58)
      - Business correspondence: Copybook "From R.S.S.", 1858-1860 (Box 80, Folder 59-61)
      - Index of Names/Index of Letters, Letterbook of Letters To RWSS, 1860-1865 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - To RWSS Correspondence, Mar-June 1860 (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Business correspondence, May-Dec 1860 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Receipts, bills, statements, promissory notes, 1860-67 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Index of Letters & Letterbooks, 1860-1869 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - RWSS miscellaneous, 1861-71 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Land lists & descriptions (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - Business correspondence, 1861 (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Account book for Indian housing - "The Great Book", 1861-1862 (Box 81, Folder 10-Sep)
      - Account book for Indian housing, 1861-1862 (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - Flyers & pamphlets (mostly reg. Kansas land), 1859-1868 (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - Deposition: Caleb W. Smith, 1862 (Box 81, Folder 13)
      - Business correspondence, 1862-1864 (Box 81, Folder 14)
      - To RWSS correspondence, 1864-65 (Box 81, Folder 15)
      - Business correspondence, Jan-Feb 1865 (Box 81, Folder 16)
      - Consolidated Index of Names, To From 7 About RWSS, from his letters & letterbooks, 1870-73 (Box 81, Folder 17)
      - Consolidated Index of Documents, To From 7 About RWSS, from his letters & letterbooks, 1870-73 (Box 81, Folder 18)
      - RWSS Correspondence, May-Dec 1870 (Box 81, Folder 19)
      - RWSS Correspondence, 1871 (Box 81, Folder 20)
      - Index of Names/Index of Documents, RWSS Telegraph Book, Sep 1870-Feb 1871 (Box 81, Folder 21)
      - RWSS Telegraph Book, Sep 1870-Feb 1871 (Box 81, Folder 22-25)
      - Correspondence, Jan-Apr 1872 (Box 81, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence, May-Aug 1872 (Box 81, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, Sep-Dec 1872 (Box 81, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, January 1873 (Box 81, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, February 1873 (Box 81, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, Mar-Apr 1873 (Box 81, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence, May-Jun 1873 (Box 81, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence, Jul-Sep 1873 (Box 81, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence, October 1873 (Box 81, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence, Nov-Dec 1973 (Box 81, Folder 35)
      - MK & T Papers & Correspondence, 1870-1873 (Box 81, Folder 36-44)
      - Index of Names/Index of Documents: To/From/About RWSS, Jan 1874-Jun 1875 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence To/From/About RWSS, Jan 1874-Jun 1875 (Box 82, Folder 11-Feb)
      - Index of Letters, Jul-Dec 1875 (Box 82, Folder 12)
      - Index of Names, Jul-Dec 1875 (Box 82, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1875 (Box 82, Folder 14-25)
      - Business correspondence, 1876 (Box 82, Folder 26)
      - Index of Names, Jan-Dec 1876 (Box 82, Folder 27)
      - Index of Letters, Jan-Dec 1876 (Box 82, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, Jan-Dec 1876 (Box 82, Folder 29-45)
    - Mary Proctor (Smith) Stevens (1828-1917)
      - Correspondence, 1851-1853 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1854-1856 (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence received, 1855-1869 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence written, 1838-1862 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Poetry, 1839-1843 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - A Keepsake, 1844 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Albert Clark Stevens (1854-1919)
      - Obituary, 1919 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Cora Caroline (Stevens) Reynolds (1856-1936)
      - Correspondence (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Introduction and Indexes (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1850s-60s (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1870-72 (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1873-78 (Box 83, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1880s-90s (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Series XI-C. Frederick Charles Stevens Generation
    - Frederick Charles Stevens (formerly Charles Frederick) (1856-1916)
      - Correspondence: Personal, 1867 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Series XI-D. Robert Sproule Stevens Generation
    - Robert Sproule Stevens (1888-1968)
      - Transcript of Audiotapes - Autobiography 1 and 2, 1965 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - (Helen) Pauline Croll Stevens (1885-1936)
      - Diary, 1903-1907 (Box 83, Folder 14-17)
      - Diary, 1904 (Box 83, Folder 18)
      - Journal, 1924-1935 (Box 83, Folder 19)
      - "Where Sunbeams Dwell" Poetry, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Series XI-E. Robert Croll Stevens Generation
    - Robert Croll Stevens (b. 1924)
      - Trip Around The World, 1935-1936 (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Series XI-F. Genealogy-related transcripts
    - Achilles family, 1836-1852 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Lee/Knight family, 1805-1828 (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Smith family, 1768-1901 (Box 83, Folder 24)